<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>consumed on Jef Claes</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/consumed/</link>
    <description>Recent content in consumed on Jef Claes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2018 21:28:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/consumed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Consumed in 2017</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2018/01/consumed-in-2017.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2018 21:28:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2018/01/consumed-in-2017.html</guid>
      <description>Another year, another 17 books, 6 shows and 3 movies consumed. Here&amp;rsquo;s this year&amp;rsquo;s highlights.
Books The Zen and Art of Motor Cycle Maintenance The author is a tormented soul on a quest to define quality. You&amp;rsquo;re his passenger, driving shot gun on a CB77 Super Hawk, in for an exhausting intellectual journey through the high mountains of reasoning. You will often fear getting lost and feel slightly anxious that the driver might drive of a cliff any moment, but he won&amp;rsquo;t.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consumed in 2016</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2016/12/consumed-in-2016.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2016 22:10:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2016/12/consumed-in-2016.html</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m keeping the tradition alive, sharing how much I&amp;rsquo;ve consumed over the last year highlighting the things that stood out. 18 books, 8 movies and 9 shows. Looks like I consumed more than other years, which probably also explains why I produced less after-hours.
Books I finished the Dark Tower series after 3 years. Following Roland Deschain and his ka-tet throughout the 8 books has been an epic adventure. Finishing Harry Potter by the time I was 18, I had little hopes to be ever dragged into such a long and captivating tale ever again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consumed in 2015</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2016/01/consumed-in-2015.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 14:49:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2016/01/consumed-in-2015.html</guid>
      <description>I started in 2014 to keep lists of everything I consume. I&amp;rsquo;ve continued this effort throughout 2015 and can now share the items I particularly enjoyed.
In 2015, I read 16 books and 3 papers, watched 3 movies and 4 shows, listened to 1 audio book and no podcasts. A lot less TV compared to 2014, but most of that time went to playing video games with some of my friends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consumed in 2014</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2015/01/consumed-in-2014.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2015 17:45:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2015/01/consumed-in-2014.html</guid>
      <description>Starting 2014, I wanted to look more closely at everything I consume. So I started keeping a list of everything I read, watch and listen to.
I started off with a markdown file on Github that quikcly evolved into a good excuse to dabble with an alternative stack. I ended up writing an event sourced node.js application on top of postgres, hosted on Heroku. I could write a post on that particular experience, but it&amp;rsquo;s safe to say this blog post captures it better than I ever could.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>