<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MVC on Jef Claes</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/mvc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in MVC on Jef Claes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Nov 2012 20:30:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/mvc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>jQuery-validate error messages in Twitter bootstrap tooltips</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2012/11/jquery-validate-error-messages-in-twitter-bootstrap-tooltips/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Nov 2012 20:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2012/11/jquery-validate-error-messages-in-twitter-bootstrap-tooltips/</guid>
      <description>At work, we&amp;rsquo;re using the combination of ASP.NET MVC3, jQuery, jQuery-validate, knockout and Twitter Bootstrap on one of our projects. Having postponed looking at the aesthetics of the client-side validation for too long, we eventually found ourselves unsatisfied with the default error labels. Wanting to save on space, we&amp;rsquo;re experimenting with the error messages being shown in a Twitter Bootstrap tooltip. After poking around for some while, I came up with something satisfactory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supporting the OPTIONS verb in ASP.NET Web API</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2012/09/supporting-the-options-verb-in-asp.net-web-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2012 18:27:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2012/09/supporting-the-options-verb-in-asp.net-web-api/</guid>
      <description>ASP.NET Web API controllers support only four HTTP verbs by convention: GET, PUT, POST and DELETE. The full list of existing HTTP verbs is more extensive though. One of those unsupported verbs which can be particularly useful for API discovery and documentation is the OPTIONS verb.
 The OPTIONS method represents a request for information about the communication options available on the request/response chain identified by the Request-URI. This method allows the client to determine the options and/or requirements associated with a resource, or the capabilities of a server, without implying a resource action or initiating a resource retrieval.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASP.NET MVC4 bundling in ASP.NET MVC3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2012/02/asp.net-mvc4-bundling-in-asp.net-mvc3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2012 20:26:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2012/02/asp.net-mvc4-bundling-in-asp.net-mvc3/</guid>
      <description>One of the new wildly evangelized features of ASP.NET MVC4 is the built-in support for bundling and minification of scripts and stylesheets.
I don&amp;rsquo;t see any reason why this new feature wouldn&amp;rsquo;t work for ASP.NET MVC3 though. If you open the packages config of an ASP.NET MVC4 beta project, you will find that bundling support lives in the Microsoft.Web.Optimization package.
&amp;lt;package id=&amp;quot;Microsoft.Web.Optimization&amp;quot; version=&amp;quot;1.0.0-beta&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;  So we should just be able to install this package for an ASP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASP.NET MVC4 Installer is incompatible with Microsoft .NET Framework 4.5</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2012/02/asp.net-mvc4-installer-is-incompatible-with-microsoft-.net-framework-4.5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2012 16:52:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2012/02/asp.net-mvc4-installer-is-incompatible-with-microsoft-.net-framework-4.5/</guid>
      <description>I tried installing ASP.NET MVC4 beta today, but seconds into the installation the WebPI already halted the process.
 ASP.NET MVC4 Installer is incompatible with Microsoft .NET Framework 4.5
 Apparently, this was documented in the ASP.NET MVC4 installation notes.
 This release is not compatible with the .NET Framework 4.5 Developer Preview. You must uninstall the .NET 4.5 Developer Preview before installing the ASP.NET MVC 4 Beta.
 I guess you have to be forgiving if you want to play with the early bits.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>