<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>community on Jef Claes</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/community/</link>
    <description>Recent content in community on Jef Claes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 21:21:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/community/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to organize a meetup</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2017/02/how-to-organize-meetup.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 21:21:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2017/02/how-to-organize-meetup.html</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve organized a few DDDBE meetups in the past, and always succeed in forgetting something. Either someone points it out well in advance, or I end up stressing last minute. This post partly serves as a checklist for myself, but it would be a welcome side effect to also see it encourage others to help out organizing future meetups. Organizing a meetup is not rocket science, having a list of what to take care of is a good start.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pieter Hintjens</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2016/04/pieter-hintjens.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 22:47:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2016/04/pieter-hintjens.html</guid>
      <description>Writing doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily always come naturally to me. It often takes me days, weeks or even months of toying with an idea, before I think it&amp;rsquo;s mature enough to put it down into writing. I can&amp;rsquo;t afford that luxury this time though, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t think of myself as much of a friend if Pieter didn&amp;rsquo;t get to read this in time.
I met Pieter the first time in a bar in Vilnius, December 2013, I accidentally ended up sitting next to him during the traditional pre-conf drinks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The first DDDBE Modellathon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2013/09/the-first-dddbe-modellathon.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2013 13:24:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2013/09/the-first-dddbe-modellathon.html</guid>
      <description>On our way back from DDD Exchange, heavily influenced by yet another immersive DDD experience, we searched for ways to keep the momentum going. Sure, we met up regularly for CQRS beers, but we felt that we could do more, better. That&amp;rsquo;s when we coined the term modellathon, something like a hackathon, but instead of writing code, we would build models.
Thanks to the effort of Mathias, Stijn and Yves, Tuesday marked the first get-together of the Belgian DDD user group in its official form.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>