<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>community on Jef Claes</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/community/</link>
    <description>Recent content in community on Jef Claes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 21:21:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/community/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to organize a meetup</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2017/02/how-to-organize-meetup.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 21:21:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2017/02/how-to-organize-meetup.html</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve organized a few DDDBE meetups in the past, and always succeed in forgetting something. Either someone points it out well in advance, or I end up stressing last minute. This post partly serves as a checklist for myself, but it would be a welcome side effect to also see it encourage others to help out organizing future meetups. Organizing a meetup is not rocket science, having a list of what to take care of is a good start.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pieter Hintjens</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2016/04/pieter-hintjens.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 22:47:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2016/04/pieter-hintjens.html</guid>
      <description>Writing doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily always come naturally to me. It often takes me days, weeks or even months of toying with an idea, before I think it&amp;rsquo;s mature enough to put it down into writing. I can&amp;rsquo;t afford that luxury this time though, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t think of myself as much of a friend if Pieter didn&amp;rsquo;t get to read this in time.
I met Pieter the first time in a bar in Vilnius, December 2013, I accidentally ended up sitting next to him during the traditional pre-conf drinks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The first DDDBE Modellathon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2013/09/the-first-dddbe-modellathon.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2013 13:24:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2013/09/the-first-dddbe-modellathon.html</guid>
      <description>On our way back from DDD Exchange, heavily influenced by yet another immersive DDD experience, we searched for ways to keep the momentum going. Sure, we met up regularly for CQRS beers, but we felt that we could do more, better. That&amp;rsquo;s when we coined the term modellathon, something like a hackathon, but instead of writing code, we would build models.
Thanks to the effort of Mathias, Stijn and Yves, Tuesday marked the first get-together of the Belgian DDD user group in its official form.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My InfoQ article on HTML5 offline web applications</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2012/05/my-infoq-article-on-html5-offline-web.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2012 20:09:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2012/05/my-infoq-article-on-html5-offline-web.html</guid>
      <description>After writing a few things on HTML5 offline web applications earlier this year, I got contacted by InfoQ to write an in-detail article on the subject for them. I hesitated at first, because I was afraid that it would feel too much like work, taking the fun out of my writing. Turns out it wasn&amp;rsquo;t like that at all. The guys at infoQ were really relaxed to work with, asking interesting questions and giving useful feedback, without forcing me into a certain direction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A real developer knows when to pull the plug</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/09/a-real-developer-knows-when-to-pull-the-plug/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2011 20:38:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/09/a-real-developer-knows-when-to-pull-the-plug/</guid>
      <description>My mini-website arealdeveloper.com will no longer be available online after tomorrow.
I slapped it together over a weekend, trying out WebMatrix, which turned out to be the perfect companion for building small things.
A pleasant surprise was the mention of &amp;lsquo;A Real Developer&amp;rsquo; by the guys at Channel9. This made the traffic go through the roof for a few days.
A few months later the site was a ghosttown. But I don&amp;rsquo;t mind, had to happen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>arealdeveloper.com mentioned on Channel9</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/05/arealdevelopercom-mentioned-on-channel9.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2011 21:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/05/arealdevelopercom-mentioned-on-channel9.html</guid>
      <description>While nosing around in the arealdeveloper.com analytics, I saw a bunch of traffic coming from Channel9. Clicking through, I found out A Real Developer was mentioned in this video (02:01). That&amp;rsquo;s a Channel9 front-page video!
That&amp;rsquo;s so awesome, I think it&amp;rsquo;s great people find it a fun project.
I have been listening to your feedback, and this Sunday I implemented some of your requests:
 Easier linking Sharing A feed Voting Comments  I try to keep everything as simple as possible, that&amp;rsquo;s why I implemented most of these features using two popular free plug-ins: AddThis and Disqus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>arealdeveloper.com</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/04/arealdevelopercom.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2011 20:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/04/arealdevelopercom.html</guid>
      <description>A Real Developer is a side-project I built over the weekend poking around with WebMatrix.

It got a little out of hand. After publishing, I showed it to a few popular tweeps, and they were kind enough to mention it. 24 hours after the launch it has gotten over 3.5k unique visitors, 39k page views (see what I did there?) and over 240 submissions. Being mentioned by Scott Hanselman and Rey Bango helps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video, slides and source from my WebSockets talk</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/04/video-slides-and-source-from-my-websockets-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2011 21:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/04/video-slides-and-source-from-my-websockets-talk/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, I gave a talk on WebSockets at HTML5 WebCamps Belgium.
 WebSockets on Fire
While the WebSockets API specification is not stable yet, various browser vendors have already implemented a prototype in their latest browser versions. Microsoft released their WebSockets prototype in December 2010. While there is no native implementation of WebSockets in IE9 just yet, for now they are providing a solution which works cross-browser, relying on a Silverlight client.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>