<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ASP.NET on Jef Claes</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/asp.net/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ASP.NET on Jef Claes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2012 20:26:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/asp.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Daydreaming about jQuery Mobile and the WebAPI</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/11/daydreaming-about-jquery-mobile-and-the-webapi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2011 17:24:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/11/daydreaming-about-jquery-mobile-and-the-webapi/</guid>
      <description>I recently blogged about programming for the future of mobile with jQuery Mobile and the WebAPI. You probably heard that jQuery Mobile 1.0 was released earlier this week. Although it will take a while before we will see some actual results from the WebAPI initiative, that shouldn&amp;rsquo;t keep us from letting our minds play with things that might be possible one day using the WebAPI.
The thoughts in this post were provoked by an interesting comment Kristof Claes left on my previous post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming for the future of mobile</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/11/programming-for-the-future-of-mobile/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2011 22:27:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/11/programming-for-the-future-of-mobile/</guid>
      <description>I have been working on something small on the side lately. I hardly have anything to show for it though, most of it is still being shaped in my head.
Anyhow, a very important part of the front-end is built using jQuery mobile. Although the framework hasn&amp;rsquo;t been released - release candidates are available though -, it&amp;rsquo;s something you should start looking into today. Why? Because the browser is the future of mobile applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Viewmodel extractors in ASP.NET MVC</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/10/viewmodel-extractors-in-asp.net-mvc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2011 20:24:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/10/viewmodel-extractors-in-asp.net-mvc/</guid>
      <description>Last week, I wrote something on assembling viewmodels in ASP.NET MVC. In that post, I said it would be nice to have a layer between my controller and my domain services that would assemble viewmodels for me. This would work one-way. In the other direction - from controller to domain services - I would just take a piece of my composite viewmodel and pass that directly to my domain services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Viewmodel assemblers in ASP.NET MVC</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/10/viewmodel-assemblers-in-asp.net-mvc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2011 20:14:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/10/viewmodel-assemblers-in-asp.net-mvc/</guid>
      <description>Working on a new ASP.NET MVC side-project, I have the luxury to experiment with new technologies, but also with different patterns and naming conventions.
Something which bugged me in a previous project was that we made our service layer return viewmodels. It worked rather well because the service layer in our MVC project was just another layer between the real domain services - where most of its work was creating viewmodels from domain objects or translating viewmodels into domain objects, so they could be passed to the domain services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Checking for anonymous types</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/05/checking-for-anonymous-types/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2011 18:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/05/checking-for-anonymous-types/</guid>
      <description>Because I blogged about anonymous types last month, I thought following method would also make an interesting post.
private static bool IsAnonymousType(Type type) { Debug.Assert(type != null, &amp;quot;Type should not be null&amp;quot;); // HACK: The only way to detect anonymous types right now. return Attribute.IsDefined(type, typeof(CompilerGeneratedAttribute), false) &amp;amp;&amp;amp; type.IsGenericType &amp;amp;&amp;amp; type.Name.Contains(&amp;quot;AnonymousType&amp;quot;) &amp;amp;&amp;amp; (type.Name.StartsWith(&amp;quot;&amp;lt;&amp;gt;&amp;quot;, StringComparison.OrdinalIgnoreCase) || type.Name.StartsWith(&amp;quot;VB$&amp;quot;, StringComparison.OrdinalIgnoreCase)) &amp;amp;&amp;amp; (type.Attributes &amp;amp; TypeAttributes.NotPublic) == TypeAttributes.NotPublic; }  For a type to be anonymous:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My thoughts on WebMatrix</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/05/my-thoughts-on-webmatrix/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 21:15:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/05/my-thoughts-on-webmatrix/</guid>
      <description>After building arealdeveloper.com, I felt like I had to do a follow-up post sharing my experiences with WebMatrix. While doing some research, I came across this post by Rob Connery. And frankly, I think it&amp;rsquo;s almost impossible for me to add something to his findings.
In a nutshell
For those who are like &amp;ldquo;tl;dr&amp;rdquo;, here are my thoughts on WebMatrix..
WebMatrix is the perfect framework to start with ASP.NET development (wish I had).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Things good to know about SQL State Server</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2010/09/things-good-to-know-about-sql-state-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2010 19:31:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2010/09/things-good-to-know-about-sql-state-server/</guid>
      <description>While installing a SQL State Server last week, I came across a few things worth sharing about the installation and use of SQL State Server.
Finding a good tutorialThere are lots of tutorials out there on how to install SQL State Server but most of them are not great. To do a basic installation you only need this Msdn documentation on how to run the Aspnet_regsql.exe tool and edit your web.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a tagcloud with jQuery and ASMX Webservices</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2010/09/building-a-tagcloud-with-jquery-and-asmx-webservices/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2010 18:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2010/09/building-a-tagcloud-with-jquery-and-asmx-webservices/</guid>
      <description>Generating tagclouds is nothing new. People have been generating tagclouds server-side since the seventies. Lately more and more tagclouds are being generated client-side.
There is nothing wrong with generating tagclouds server-side. Telerik has a great tagcloud server control. Generating tagclouds server-side can bring some overhead though, so depending on the scenario and the requirements you might decide to do it client-side. There are a ton of fancy ready-to-use jQuery tagcloud plug-ins out there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Switching with non-constant cases in C#</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2010/07/switching-with-non-constant-cases-in-c/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2010 22:25:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2010/07/switching-with-non-constant-cases-in-c/</guid>
      <description>Last week I came across a scenario where I wanted to switch over non-constants (aka variables), but while I was compiling I got Compiler Error CS0150 (A constant value is expected). This is one of those things I always forget. You can&amp;rsquo;t use variables in your case statements because the C# compiler doesn&amp;rsquo;t allow you to. It&amp;rsquo;s very logical though, the compiler forces you to use constants because otherwise there is no way of knowing there are equal case statements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Follow up: Eliminating redundant eventhandlers using a dictionary to map controls</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2010/07/follow-up-eliminating-redundant-eventhandlers-using-a-dictionary-to-map-controls/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2010 20:55:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2010/07/follow-up-eliminating-redundant-eventhandlers-using-a-dictionary-to-map-controls/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I blogged on &amp;lsquo;WebForms refactoring: Eliminating redundant eventhandlers using a dictionary to map controls&#39;. In this post I went from bad code to better code. A smart reader gave me some good pointers on how to improve this code some more. Another iteration was necessary.
Losing the LinqIn the previous iteration I used Linq to search my dictionary.
 1: var res = mappings.Where(map =&amp;gt; map.Key.Equals((CheckBox)sender)).First();  This is overhead, because the dictionary implements an indexer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebForms refactoring: Eliminating redundant eventhandlers using a dictionary to map controls</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2010/07/webforms-refactoring-eliminating-redundant-eventhandlers-using-a-dictionary-to-map-controls/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2010 21:35:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2010/07/webforms-refactoring-eliminating-redundant-eventhandlers-using-a-dictionary-to-map-controls/</guid>
      <description>Last week I came across a problem which seemed trivial at first sight, but turned out to be a pretty fun refactoring challenge.
The scenarioThe real problem was a bit more complex, but for simplicity&amp;rsquo;s sake I made this example. In this form there are three checkboxes which map with the textboxes next to them. If the checkbox gets unchecked the corresponding textboxes should be cleared.

First iterationI warn you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The state of the client-side ASP.NET Ajax 4.0 framework</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2010/04/the-state-of-the-client-side-asp.net-ajax-4.0-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2010 21:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2010/04/the-state-of-the-client-side-asp.net-ajax-4.0-framework/</guid>
      <description>The people who follow my blog might remember the ASP.NET Ajax 4.0 series. In these series I showed some of the core features of the ASP.NET Ajax 4.0 beta javascript library.
In January Microsoft told us that they would ship the ASP.NET Ajax 4.0 library as a part of the Microsoft Ajax framework, together with the release of ASP.NET 4.0. A few days ago I was ready to dig in the library a little deeper, but I found out that most of the documentation and resources I used to consult, had moved or had disappeared.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Webforms lessons learned the hard way (Part 2)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2010/02/webforms-lessons-learned-the-hard-way-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2010 17:43:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2010/02/webforms-lessons-learned-the-hard-way-part-2/</guid>
      <description>If you missed part 1, you can find it here.
Use the built-in goodiesASP.NET Webforms has a lot of good stuff built into it. Do your homework before you start building the next big Webforms thing! A perfect example of this is ASP.NET Membership. ASP.NET provides an out-of-box membership solution. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen people who were to lazy to do some research or thought they could do better and ended up with a solution which put its doors wide open to people with bad intentions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Webforms lessons learned the hard way (Part 1)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2010/02/webforms-lessons-learned-the-hard-way-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2010 16:22:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2010/02/webforms-lessons-learned-the-hard-way-part-1/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been spending a lot of my days in Webforms the last two years. In this post I want to share some best practices I&amp;rsquo;ve learned the hard way over these years. A lot of MVC developers might think this post comes a bit late (who still cares about Webforms?!), I do think (in the real world) a lot of the ASP.NET developers are still using Webforms. This post is directly targeting them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The problem that ViewStateMode solves</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2009/12/the-problem-that-viewstatemode-solves/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2009 16:55:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2009/12/the-problem-that-viewstatemode-solves/</guid>
      <description>A new feature of ASP.NET 4.0 is the ViewStateMode property on a Control.
 You can use the ViewStateMode property to enable view state for an individual control even if view state is disabled for the page.
Source:Msdn
 In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll try to give this new feature a chance to shine and show it&amp;rsquo;s use.
Problem to solve: Disable ViewState on the Page and enable it on an individual Control.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Response.RedirectPermanent in .NET 3.5 and older</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2009/12/response.redirectpermanent-in-.net-3.5-and-older/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2009 17:50:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2009/12/response.redirectpermanent-in-.net-3.5-and-older/</guid>
      <description>One of the new features in ASP.NET 4.0 is permanently redirecting to a page using Response.RedirectPermanent.
 It is common practice in Web applications to move pages and other content around over time, which can lead to an accumulation of stale links in search engines. In ASP.NET, developers have traditionally handled requests to old URLs by using by using the Response.Redirect method to forward a request to the new URL. However, the Redirect method issues an HTTP 302 Found (temporary redirect) response, which results in an extra HTTP round trip when users attempt to access the old URLs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book review: Professional Refactoring in C# &amp; ASP.NET</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2009/11/book-review-professional-refactoring-in-c#-asp.net/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2009 19:37:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2009/11/book-review-professional-refactoring-in-c#-asp.net/</guid>
      <description>Three months ago I was looking up to refactoring a legacy ASP.NET Webforms application. Although I was familiar with refactoring, I ordered &amp;ldquo;Professional Refactoring in C# &amp;amp; ASP.NET&amp;rdquo; by Daniejel Arsenovski to get deeper into refactoring.
The titleAlthough the title states &amp;ldquo;Professional&amp;rdquo;, I think this book should find it&amp;rsquo;s main audience in coding novices. Another problem with the title is the word ASP.NET in it. The book has one chapter covering ASP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why the javascript beforeunload event is incomplete</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2009/09/why-the-javascript-beforeunload-event-is-incomplete/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2009 21:13:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2009/09/why-the-javascript-beforeunload-event-is-incomplete/</guid>
      <description>The onbeforeunload event fires when a page is being unloaded.
In the intranet webapplications world customers pretty often ask to show a warning when a user leaves a page (by closing the browser, closing a tab, clicking a link,..). This feature is specifically very interesting for data-input-driven webforms where one wrong click can make ten minutes of work undone.
Last week I had to implement this feature in a huge webform which is causing lots of postbacks (firing the onbeforeunload event).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debugging &#34;SubReport could not be shown.&#34;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2009/09/debugging-subreport-could-not-be-shown./</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2009 18:41:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2009/09/debugging-subreport-could-not-be-shown./</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been upgrading a local report which contains multiple subreports, and yes I got that &amp;ldquo;SubReport could not be shown.&amp;rdquo; error more than once.
Debugging this error is a pain in the a.. All you get is &amp;ldquo;SubReport could not be shown.&amp;quot;, making me want to punch my screen and scream &amp;ldquo;BUT WHY?&amp;ldquo;Just before breaking my screen and going on full tilt, I decided to take a step back and run through my checklist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three common mistakes you should avoid when starting with Web Page Resources in ASP.NET</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2009/09/three-common-mistakes-you-should-avoid-when-starting-with-web-page-resources-in-asp.net/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2009 20:04:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2009/09/three-common-mistakes-you-should-avoid-when-starting-with-web-page-resources-in-asp.net/</guid>
      <description>This is a list of of three common mistakes made by developers who start using Web Page Resources in ASP.NET.
1. Not using the right format for the name of a local resources fileThe format of the name of a local resources file should be: PageName.PageExtension.resx.
If you don&amp;rsquo;t add the page extension (Aspx, Ascx), you will get the Exception &amp;ldquo;The resource object with key &amp;lsquo;PageTitle&amp;rsquo; was not found.&amp;quot;.
2. Not adding an App_LocalResources folder to each subfolderEach subfolder must have it&amp;rsquo;s own App_LocalResources folder, else ASP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Curt Christianson (Part II)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2009/01/interview-with-curt-christianson-part-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2009 20:34:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2009/01/interview-with-curt-christianson-part-ii/</guid>
      <description>This is part II of the interview with Curt Christianson. For Part I go here.
Part 2: Technology Let me ask you some general questions about building a web application. What is your advise on setting up the layers of a web application. In the web application I&amp;rsquo;m currently working on we chose a not so standard architecture I guess. We have multiple &amp;ldquo;modules&amp;rdquo;, which are folders in practice. In the root of these modules we hold our aspx pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Curt Christianson (Part I)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2009/01/interview-with-curt-christianson-part-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2009 19:42:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2009/01/interview-with-curt-christianson-part-i/</guid>
      <description>Curt Christianson is one of the administrators of forums.asp.net. Last month I stumbled across his blog, and felt like I had to do an interview with him. And here we are!
I have divided his interview in two parts:
 His career and his life Some techtalk on mainly ASP.NET webproject-architecture mixed with a bit of AJAX and WPF  Part 1: Career and life Who are you? Where do you live?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>