<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>talks on Jef Claes</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/talks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in talks on Jef Claes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2015 15:47:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/talks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Slides from my talk &#34;Evil by Design&#34; at Build Stuff</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2015/11/slides-from-my-talk-evil-by-design-at.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2015 15:47:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2015/11/slides-from-my-talk-evil-by-design-at.html</guid>
      <description>Third time attending Build Stuff, first time doing a talk. I&amp;rsquo;m happy that it&amp;rsquo;s out of the way and can now just enjoy the conference, but I&amp;rsquo;m even more excited that it was well-received! The talk should have been recorded, but you can already find the abstract and slides below.
 Last year I ventured into the domain of (online) gambling. Given that the industry has been around since forever, I expected most problems to be of the technical kind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NCrafts Eventstorming slides</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2014/05/ncrafts-eventstorming-slides.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2014 15:22:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2014/05/ncrafts-eventstorming-slides.html</guid>
      <description>Me and Tom just finished doing our Event storming workshop at NCrafts Paris. Although we made a few mistakes along the way, feedback on the workshop was great. I hope to put something out about what we learned facilitating later this week. People talked, discovered and eventually learned a new domain in under two hours. The domain? Two minutes before the workshop we found a domain expert prepared to talk about his coupon start-up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What if we stored events instead of state? - slides</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2014/05/what-if-we-stored-events-instead-of.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2014 17:41:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2014/05/what-if-we-stored-events-instead-of.html</guid>
      <description>I just returned from Croatia, where I got to speak twice at the second edition of The Geek Gathering.
Being such a young conference, I had no idea what to expect. Turns out they have a good thing going on; a small, local and very personal approach to conferences. Speakers both local and international, covering topics that serve the community, not their employer.
Together with Tom, I preached Alberto&amp;lsquo;s Event Storming during a four hour long workshop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DDDBE slides on the Ubiquitous Language</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2014/02/dddbe-slides-on-ubiquitous-language.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2014 18:04:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2014/02/dddbe-slides-on-ubiquitous-language.html</guid>
      <description>Monday, I and four others did a DDDBE session on the strategic side of Domain Driven Design.
My talk covered the Ubiquitous Language, and can be found on Slideshare. I might end up writing down the content of the talk as well - some images are meaningless without words. Evaluating feedback, I think the biggest mistake we made was keeping some things too abstract - curse of knowledge at work. If we get the chance to repeat the session, we need to make sure to weave a practical story through our talks to make them stick.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Event storming workshop slides</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2013/11/event-storming-workshop-slides.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2013 19:56:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2013/11/event-storming-workshop-slides.html</guid>
      <description>At Euricom, we quarterly all retreat to headquarters for a day of sharing and learning. This time, I and others organized and facilitated an event storming workshop.
After a short introduction on event storming participants were initiated to the domain of Cambio CarSharing - which is packed with behaviour. After that, seven groups of five (+ one domain expert) spread out across the office, and spent two slots of twenty minutes modeling the domain - with two extra slots for feedback.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slides from my talk on the Ubiquitous Language</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2013/09/slides-from-my-talk-on-ubiquitous.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2013 16:34:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2013/09/slides-from-my-talk-on-ubiquitous.html</guid>
      <description>I just returned from our yearly Euricom retreat. This year, all forty of us got to spend four days in the South of Spain. Where we had longish sessions and a few workshops last year, we experimented with shorter talks this year - a la lightning talks, TEDx style.
This format made it possible for everyone to speak, but also forced the speaker to keep the scope of the talk focused, and to organize the information in a way that attendees can get the gist of it in only twelve minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Post Web.NET Europe</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2012/10/post-webnet-europe.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2012 20:35:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2012/10/post-webnet-europe.html</guid>
      <description>I attended and spoke at Web.NET Europe in Milan over the weekend. This was only my fourth full day- or more conference (Techdays Belgium, TechEd Berlin and HTML5 WebCamps), but it was undoubtedly the best one so far.
The quality of the sessions was definitely not inferior to those of bigger conferences. I especially enjoyed the talks on SignalR, OAuth and scaling data (I included some of my notes below). The strength of this conference doesn&amp;rsquo;t lie in the exceptional speakers or sessions though, but in its cozy size and the type of attendees it attracts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slides and code from my Web.NET Europe REST and ASP.NET Web API session</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2012/10/slides-and-code-from-my-webnet-europe.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2012 00:16:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2012/10/slides-and-code-from-my-webnet-europe.html</guid>
      <description>I just returned to the hotel after attending and speaking at Web.NET Europe 2012. There were multiple sessions on ASP.NET Web API today, and I was responsible for delivering the first one of the day. Being first, and to avoid overlap with others, I tried to lay a solid foundation by focusing on the REST and ASP.NET Web API basics: resources, identifiers, representations, verbs and hypermedia.
More people than I expected showed up for my talk; somewhere around 50 to 70 attendees, I guess.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>