<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>story on Jef Claes</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/story/</link>
    <description>Recent content in story on Jef Claes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2017 08:48:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/story/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>From human decisions, to suggestions to automated decisions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2017/07/from-human-decisions-to-suggestions-to.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2017 08:48:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2017/07/from-human-decisions-to-suggestions-to.html</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to share this experience for a while, but it took me a while to come up with a story and example I could use in a blog post.
I help out during the weekends in a small family run magic shop. I&amp;rsquo;m the third generation working in the shop. My great-grandfather always hoped that his only son would follow in his footsteps as a carpenter. But at only eighteen years old, my grandfather said goodbye to the chisels and sawdust, and set out for the big city to chase his dream of becoming a world class magician.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eventual consistency in the Wild West</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2014/05/eventual-consistency-in-wild-west.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2014 18:01:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2014/05/eventual-consistency-in-wild-west.html</guid>
      <description>San Francisco, 1852. With the California Gold Rush at its peak, successful gold-seekers wanted to protect all their precious gold nuggets by storing them in a strong safe. At the time, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t that easy to have access to a safe though. At the very beginning, it were just a few local merchants that owned one. Not much later, bankers swamped the area hoping to get their piece of the pie - bringing the strongest safes money can buy.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>