<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Web API on Jef Claes</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/web-api/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Web API on Jef Claes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2012 00:16:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/web-api/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The 7 R&#39;s of Hypermedia</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2012/09/the-7-rs-of-hypermedia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2012 21:42:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2012/09/the-7-rs-of-hypermedia/</guid>
      <description>While most REST concepts are rather easy to grok, there is one concept which I found harder to understand at first: Hypermedia. Let it be that without this concept, you&amp;rsquo;re missing out on an extremely important strength of REST. Hypermedia enables you to build dumb - or smart, depending on your perspective - clients, which are mostly driven by the server. Practically, this is implemented as resources embedding links which allow the client to discover and navigate through your RESTful service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slides and code from my Tunisia REST and ASP.NET Web API session</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2012/09/slides-and-code-from-my-tunisia-rest-and-asp.net-web-api-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2012 08:55:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2012/09/slides-and-code-from-my-tunisia-rest-and-asp.net-web-api-session/</guid>
      <description>I just returned from a four day trip to Tunisia with Euricom. Next to indulging on the sun, food and all-inclusive cocktails, getting to know each other in a less professional setting, we spent somewhere around half of our days - and this is a rather generous estimate - doing technical sessions and workshops.I gave a 90 minute long crash course on REST and ASP.NET Web API.
Content
REST Concepts Architectural values Left overs  ASP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supporting the OPTIONS verb in ASP.NET Web API</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2012/09/supporting-the-options-verb-in-asp.net-web-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2012 18:27:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2012/09/supporting-the-options-verb-in-asp.net-web-api/</guid>
      <description>ASP.NET Web API controllers support only four HTTP verbs by convention: GET, PUT, POST and DELETE. The full list of existing HTTP verbs is more extensive though. One of those unsupported verbs which can be particularly useful for API discovery and documentation is the OPTIONS verb.
 The OPTIONS method represents a request for information about the communication options available on the request/response chain identified by the Request-URI. This method allows the client to determine the options and/or requirements associated with a resource, or the capabilities of a server, without implying a resource action or initiating a resource retrieval.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASP.NET Web API error detail policy now defaults to the custom errors configuration</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2012/08/asp.net-web-api-error-detail-policy-now-defaults-to-the-custom-errors-configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2012 08:50:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2012/08/asp.net-web-api-error-detail-policy-now-defaults-to-the-custom-errors-configuration/</guid>
      <description>While working on an already updated ASP.NET Web API project, I noticed an extra value in the IncludeErrorDetailPolicy enumeration. The IncludeErrorDetailPolicy configuration tells the Web API host when it&amp;rsquo;s allowed to include full error details in responses. Before updating, the RC version of the IncludeErrorDetailPolicy enumeration only had three possible values: LocalOnly, Always and Never. With the released version comes a new value: Default.
// Summary: // Use the default behavior for the host environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should I unit- or integration test my ASP.NET Web API services?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2012/07/should-i-unit-or-integration-test-my-asp.net-web-api-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2012 22:37:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2012/07/should-i-unit-or-integration-test-my-asp.net-web-api-services/</guid>
      <description>Over the last two weeks, preparing for a talk, I have been doing some research on ASP.NET Web API. After working my way through the API, and the implementation of certain features, I looked at testing.
Similar to ASP.NET MVC, Web API allows you to create relatively small building blocks, which can replace parts of, or be added to an existing default global setup. This makes it possible for us to test each component in isolation: controllers, dependency resolvers, filters, serialization, type formatters, messagehandlers and routing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>