<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Architecture on Jef Claes</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/architecture/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Architecture on Jef Claes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 May 2014 17:41:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/architecture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Event storming workshop slides</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2013/11/event-storming-workshop-slides/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2013 19:56:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2013/11/event-storming-workshop-slides/</guid>
      <description>At Euricom, we quarterly all retreat to headquarters for a day of sharing and learning. This time, I and others organized and facilitated an event storming workshop.
After a short introduction on event storming participants were initiated to the domain of Cambio CarSharing - which is packed with behaviour. After that, seven groups of five (+ one domain expert) spread out across the office, and spent two slots of twenty minutes modeling the domain - with two extra slots for feedback.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An event sourced aggregate</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2013/10/an-event-sourced-aggregate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2013 18:36:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2013/10/an-event-sourced-aggregate/</guid>
      <description>Last week I shared my theoretical understanding of event sourcing. Today, I want to make an attempt at making that theory tangible by implementing an event sourced aggregate.
In traditional systems, we only persist the current state of an object.

In event sourced systems, we don&amp;rsquo;t persist the current state of an object, but the sequence of events that caused the object to be in the current state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My understanding of event sourcing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2013/10/my-understanding-of-event-sourcing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2013 18:32:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2013/10/my-understanding-of-event-sourcing/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been studying event sourcing from a distance for little over a year now; reading online material and going through some of the excellent OS code. Unfortunately, there would be no value introducing it into my current project - it would even be a terrible idea, so I decided to satisfy my inquisitiveness by consolidating and sharing my understanding of the concept.
Domain events
**
**An event is something that happened in the past.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Actor Model in COBOL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2013/09/actor-model-in-cobol/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2013 16:38:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2013/09/actor-model-in-cobol/</guid>
      <description>In an Actor system, each Actor acts as a self-contained and autonomous component. An Actor can only communicate with other Actors by exchanging messages - they are not allowed to share state. Messages are handled asynchronously, and are nondeterministic. The location of Actors should be transparent; they can either live on the same machine, or on a distributed system. These properties make the Actor Model a great fit for parallel and distributed computing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inheritance is like Jenga</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2013/08/inheritance-is-like-jenga/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2013 18:18:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2013/08/inheritance-is-like-jenga/</guid>
      <description>These last few days, I have been working on a piece of our codebase that accidentally got very inheritance heavy.
When it comes to inheritance versus composition, there are a few widely accepted rules of thumb out there. While prefer composition over inheritance doesn&amp;rsquo;t cover the nuances, it&amp;rsquo;s not terrible advice; composition will statistically often be the better solution. Steve McConnell&amp;rsquo;s composition defines a &amp;lsquo;has a&amp;rsquo;- relationship while inheritance defines an &amp;lsquo;is a&amp;rsquo;-relationship, gives you a more nuanced and simple tool to apply to a scenario.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When your commands spell CUD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2013/08/when-your-commands-spell-cud/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2013 19:08:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2013/08/when-your-commands-spell-cud/</guid>
      <description>A good while ago, I blogged on commands (and queries). After exploring various flavors, I eventually settled on this one; commands, handlers and an in-memory bus that serves as a command executor.
Commands help you in supporting the ubiquitous language by explicitly capturing user intent at the boundaries of your system - think use cases. You can look at them as messages that are being sent to your domain. In this regard, they also serve as a layer over your domain - decoupling the inside from the outside, allowing you to gradually introduce concepts on the inside, without breaking the outside.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accidental entities - what about the UI?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2013/06/accidental-entities-what-about-the-ui/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2013 16:24:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2013/06/accidental-entities-what-about-the-ui/</guid>
      <description>This post is a follow-up to my previous blog post &amp;ldquo;[Accidental entities
 you don&amp;rsquo;t need that identity](http://www.jefclaes.be/2013/05/accidental-entities-you-dont-need-that.html)&amp;quot;.  In that post, we followed a consultant building an application for a car rental. One of the requirements was that the CEO could manage a collection of available colors. Although the tools at our disposal - a relational database and NHibernate - wanted to trick us into making a car reference one of these available colors by its identifier, we found out that the CEO really thinks of a car&amp;rsquo;s color as a value, and does not care about a color&amp;rsquo;s identity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accidental entities - you don&#39;t need that identity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2013/05/accidental-entities-you-dont-need-that-identity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2013 16:27:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2013/05/accidental-entities-you-dont-need-that-identity/</guid>
      <description>An entity is identified by an identifier, while value objects are identified by their value.
If I make a living renting cars to tourists, I might not care the least about the identity of the colors the cars came in. I just care about their value; Rosso Corsa, Azurro Metallic&amp;hellip; If I repaint the car, the color changes, and the previous color is abandoned as a whole.
However, if I were a car paint manufacturer, I would care a great deal about the identity of a color.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some experimental infrastructure for IronMQ pull </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2013/03/some-experimental-infrastructure-for-ironmq-pull/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2013 17:29:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2013/03/some-experimental-infrastructure-for-ironmq-pull/</guid>
      <description>I wrote about using IronMQ as a cloud-based message queue last week. In that post I explained that you can go at using IronMQ in two ways; either you pull from the queue yourself, or you let IronMQ push messages from the queue to your HTTP endpoints. At first sight, the latter allows you to outsource more infrastructure to their side, but upon closer inspection it also introduces other concerns: security, local debugging and scalability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First IronMQ impressions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2013/03/first-ironmq-impressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 16:45:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2013/03/first-ironmq-impressions/</guid>
      <description>First time I touched messaging was in the first few years of my professional life working on software that supported fire departments in their day-to-day activities. The dispatching software would send messages to a proprietary broker, which in its turn would forward them to interested subscribers; other dispatching clients, or services. To ensure availability, the broker component could failover to a different machine, but that was about it. It didn&amp;rsquo;t allow you to queue or retry messages; if you weren&amp;rsquo;t up when the messages were forwarded, you would never receive them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding the R to CQS: some storage options</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2013/02/adding-the-r-to-cqs-some-storage-options/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2013 17:57:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2013/02/adding-the-r-to-cqs-some-storage-options/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been writing quite a bit about CQS (or command and query separation) lately. In my last post on using events, I already hinted towards bringing in the R; command and query responsibility separation.
With CQS, commands can mutate data, while queries can only read that data. CQRS takes this one step further, and assigns commands and queries each a dedicated model; we now talk of a write side, and a read side.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>