<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Architecture on Jef Claes</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/architecture/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Architecture on Jef Claes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 May 2014 17:41:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/architecture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Accidental entities - what about the UI?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2013/06/accidental-entities-what-about-the-ui/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2013 16:24:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2013/06/accidental-entities-what-about-the-ui/</guid>
      <description>This post is a follow-up to my previous blog post &amp;ldquo;[Accidental entities
 you don&amp;rsquo;t need that identity](http://www.jefclaes.be/2013/05/accidental-entities-you-dont-need-that.html)&amp;quot;.  In that post, we followed a consultant building an application for a car rental. One of the requirements was that the CEO could manage a collection of available colors. Although the tools at our disposal - a relational database and NHibernate - wanted to trick us into making a car reference one of these available colors by its identifier, we found out that the CEO really thinks of a car&amp;rsquo;s color as a value, and does not care about a color&amp;rsquo;s identity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accidental entities - you don&#39;t need that identity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2013/05/accidental-entities-you-dont-need-that-identity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2013 16:27:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2013/05/accidental-entities-you-dont-need-that-identity/</guid>
      <description>An entity is identified by an identifier, while value objects are identified by their value.
If I make a living renting cars to tourists, I might not care the least about the identity of the colors the cars came in. I just care about their value; Rosso Corsa, Azurro Metallic&amp;hellip; If I repaint the car, the color changes, and the previous color is abandoned as a whole.
However, if I were a car paint manufacturer, I would care a great deal about the identity of a color.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some experimental infrastructure for IronMQ pull </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2013/03/some-experimental-infrastructure-for-ironmq-pull/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2013 17:29:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2013/03/some-experimental-infrastructure-for-ironmq-pull/</guid>
      <description>I wrote about using IronMQ as a cloud-based message queue last week. In that post I explained that you can go at using IronMQ in two ways; either you pull from the queue yourself, or you let IronMQ push messages from the queue to your HTTP endpoints. At first sight, the latter allows you to outsource more infrastructure to their side, but upon closer inspection it also introduces other concerns: security, local debugging and scalability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First IronMQ impressions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2013/03/first-ironmq-impressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 16:45:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2013/03/first-ironmq-impressions/</guid>
      <description>First time I touched messaging was in the first few years of my professional life working on software that supported fire departments in their day-to-day activities. The dispatching software would send messages to a proprietary broker, which in its turn would forward them to interested subscribers; other dispatching clients, or services. To ensure availability, the broker component could failover to a different machine, but that was about it. It didn&amp;rsquo;t allow you to queue or retry messages; if you weren&amp;rsquo;t up when the messages were forwarded, you would never receive them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding the R to CQS: some storage options</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2013/02/adding-the-r-to-cqs-some-storage-options/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2013 17:57:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2013/02/adding-the-r-to-cqs-some-storage-options/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been writing quite a bit about CQS (or command and query separation) lately. In my last post on using events, I already hinted towards bringing in the R; command and query responsibility separation.
With CQS, commands can mutate data, while queries can only read that data. CQRS takes this one step further, and assigns commands and queries each a dedicated model; we now talk of a write side, and a read side.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>