<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>javascript on Jef Claes</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/javascript/</link>
    <description>Recent content in javascript on Jef Claes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2010 19:30:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/javascript/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>HTML5: New in the javascript Selector API</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2010/11/html5-new-in-the-javascript-selector-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2010 19:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2010/11/html5-new-in-the-javascript-selector-api/</guid>
      <description>Because I finally got the MCTS 70-536 certification out of the way, I can start experimenting with some fun stuff again. One of the things on the top of my list is HTML5. I started reading the book Pro HTML5 Programming, so expect more posts on HTML5 in the near future.
In this post I will show you two new methods in the javascript Selector API which are extremely useful to find elements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The state of the client-side ASP.NET Ajax 4.0 framework</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2010/04/the-state-of-the-client-side-asp.net-ajax-4.0-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2010 21:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2010/04/the-state-of-the-client-side-asp.net-ajax-4.0-framework/</guid>
      <description>The people who follow my blog might remember the ASP.NET Ajax 4.0 series. In these series I showed some of the core features of the ASP.NET Ajax 4.0 beta javascript library.
In January Microsoft told us that they would ship the ASP.NET Ajax 4.0 library as a part of the Microsoft Ajax framework, together with the release of ASP.NET 4.0. A few days ago I was ready to dig in the library a little deeper, but I found out that most of the documentation and resources I used to consult, had moved or had disappeared.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book review: Object-Oriented JavaScript</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2010/02/book-review-object-oriented-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2010 19:47:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2010/02/book-review-object-oriented-javascript/</guid>
      <description>Although I&amp;rsquo;ve made my feet wet with various JavaScript frameworks, I am not a JavaScript hero at all. This might be one of the disadvantages of being a WebForms developer and having great toolkits at hand like the AJAX Control Toolkit and Telerik RADControls.
Because you really can&amp;rsquo;t call yourself a webdeveloper without having some understanding of JavaScript I decided to order Object-Oriented Javascript by Stoyan Stefanov.
This book really handles the language itself.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>