<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>General on Jef Claes</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/general/</link>
    <description>Recent content in General on Jef Claes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2009 18:57:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/general/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking back, moving forward (New years post)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2009/12/looking-back-moving-forward-new-years-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2009 18:57:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2009/12/looking-back-moving-forward-new-years-post/</guid>
      <description>In this post I&amp;rsquo;m going to reflect on the year that&amp;rsquo;s almost finished and the year to come.
I came up with a few topics that are worth discussing in this post.
My career
I don&amp;rsquo;t think I ever mentioned where I work. The first of January I will be working 18 months for Ferranti. The only company I&amp;rsquo;ve worked for since I graduated.
The first project I&amp;rsquo;ve ever worked on was a rather big one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My trip to Madrid in ten pictures</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2009/11/my-trip-to-madrid-in-ten-pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2009 20:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2009/11/my-trip-to-madrid-in-ten-pictures/</guid>
      <description>Last week I went to Madrid with my family-in-law to visit my girlfriend&amp;rsquo;s brother and cousin.
Although our stay there was rather short (only four days), we visited some of the most impressive places in Madrid:
 - Stadium Real Madrid
 The Royal Palace Prado Museum Queen Sofia Museum Buen Retiro Park Plaza Mayor &amp;hellip;   As always my girlfriend took lots of pictures, you can find my favorites below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why code reviews should be a teamthing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2009/08/why-code-reviews-should-be-a-teamthing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2009 19:22:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2009/08/why-code-reviews-should-be-a-teamthing/</guid>
      <description>Often code reviews are done by one person, the technical lead of your team.
In my opinion it&amp;rsquo;s better to make each developer of your team do code reviews.
My arguments Having all developers doing code reviews enforces well-documented coding standards.. Which also leads to discussions about what these coding standards should be. Each developer is forced to understand the workflow of an application which isn&amp;rsquo;t his, which expands his domain knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My holiday in France in five pictures</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2009/08/my-holiday-in-france-in-five-pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2009 19:12:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2009/08/my-holiday-in-france-in-five-pictures/</guid>
      <description>Last week I went on a holiday to France with my girlfriend and her family.
Because pictures say more than words..
One: The location - Laguepie, Albi
Two: The house and &amp;ldquo;la piscine&amp;quot;
Three: Me enjoying the sun
Four: Only in France you find a 1955 Peugeot 403 with numberplates just standing there next to the road
Five: Random picture of one of the towns next to Laguepie
Looking forward to the next holiday :)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>