<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>General on Jef Claes</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/general/</link>
    <description>Recent content in General on Jef Claes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 15:58:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/general/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2012 Annual Review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2012/12/2012-annual-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 15:58:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2012/12/2012-annual-review/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s that time of the year again where I take some time to look back on the year passed and peek at the year ahead. This is mostly a post I like to write up for myself, forcing reflection.
The biggest personal changes this year were moving out of my parents&amp;rsquo; place, and my girlfriend&amp;rsquo;s decision to study medicine after graduating as a Master of Arts earlier this year. I had no idea how things would turn out once we lived together, but so far we have been doing great.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2012&#39;s most read posts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2012/12/2012s-most-read-posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2012 15:53:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2012/12/2012s-most-read-posts/</guid>
      <description>I look forward to writing this post each year; it&amp;rsquo;s by far the easiest one to write, and it provides me with an occasion to look back on previous years (2009, 2010, 2011). It&amp;rsquo;s entertaining - and shameful too - to see what kept me busy back then, which opinions I held, and which technologies and techniques are still relevant in the meanwhile. Anyways, here it goes.
The most read post this year, with 37.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning: the Hacker Way</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2012/03/learning-the-hacker-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2012 11:08:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2012/03/learning-the-hacker-way/</guid>
      <description>I have had a fair amount of discussions on continuous learning and knowledge sharing the past few days. It became rather obvious that a lot of us have developed their own techniques, but also that maybe most of us are still in search of more efficient techniques. Having gone through several phases myself, I would like to share my current way of learning: the Hacker Way.
Here are some snippets taken from a recent letter from Mark Zuckerberg addressed to the Facebook shareholders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>There&#39;s no place for monogamy in technology</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2012/02/theres-no-place-for-monogamy-in-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2012 08:43:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2012/02/theres-no-place-for-monogamy-in-technology/</guid>
      <description>In this post I would like to share some of my thoughts on a recent post by James Hague titled &amp;lsquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t Fall in Love With Your Technology&amp;rsquo;. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t read that post yet, please do, it&amp;rsquo;s so short that me summarizing it here would be silly.
I think there is nothing wrong with falling in love with your technology per se. If you want to have a fair relationship with your technology, you have to invest in her.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2011 Annual Review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/12/2011-annual-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2011 21:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/12/2011-annual-review/</guid>
      <description>Since the end of the year is approaching, I would like to look back on 2011 and take a peek at 2012. Unlike the years before, I&amp;rsquo;m hardly setting any goals this year. Interests change so quickly, and new opportunities present themselves so regularly, I feel like it might be ignorant to set these things in stone.
My career
The year started out interesting, working on a brand new product for fire departments at Ferranti Computer Systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2011&#39;s most read posts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/12/2011s-most-read-posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2011 19:33:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/12/2011s-most-read-posts/</guid>
      <description>I compiled a list of most popular posts that were published on this blog in 2011. Unlike last year, and the year before that, this year it&amp;rsquo;s not a strict top five list. While analyzing the statistics, I found out that a few topics -covered over multiple posts - were popular this year.
Preparing for my HTML5 Webcamps session on WebSockets, I wrote a few posts on the Microsoft WebSockets prototype.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commute hacking: Chromapaper</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/10/commute-hacking-chromapaper/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2011 17:36:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/10/commute-hacking-chromapaper/</guid>
      <description>Since I changed jobs, I do my daily commute by train. This adds two hours of leasure time to the day, which I used to lose in traffic.
So far, I have been spending these two won hours programming and/or reading. I have been looking for a way to read online content offline on my laptop. Searching for software that could make this happen, I mostly came across programs which would mirror a whole site locally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comfortably numb</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/09/comfortably-numb/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2011 20:51:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/09/comfortably-numb/</guid>
      <description>Something that can bother me tremendously is being surrounded by people who are in a constant state of being comfortably numb. People who don&amp;rsquo;t welcome change, try to scare away new concepts and are just too much at home in their comfort zone. Some are perfectly happy filling their days keeping up appearances of being busy. They don&amp;rsquo;t care about self-improvement, but only care about augmenting their paychecks by accumulating as much legacy baggage as possible, with the sole intention of being perceived as an irreplaceable asset to the company, whilst not having to leave their comfort zone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building small things</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/09/building-small-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2011 16:35:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/09/building-small-things/</guid>
      <description>Due to the nature of things we build in our day to day job, writing software can wear out even the most fit of us.
Most software jobs make you constantly deal with complexity. The amount of things which can lead to a complex software project are immense. A poor first design, and failure to redesign. External dependencies, which seem to behave different every time around. Or just the complexity of the problems itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Things I read</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/08/things-i-read/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2011 21:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/08/things-i-read/</guid>
      <description>Over the years I have collected an impressive collection of technology related feeds in my Google Reader account. Lately, I find myself neglecting most of my Google Reader subscriptions, and getting my information from a few specific sources. It just has become too much of a chore to sift out the really interesting posts.
That&amp;rsquo;s why I have put my faith in the community to do the dirty work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High Hopes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/08/high-hopes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2011 20:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/08/high-hopes/</guid>
      <description>Last week, I resigned from my job at Ferranti Computer Systems. Three years ago, days after receiving my Graduate Diploma in Applied Computer Science, I had my first real-world working experience at Ferranti Computer Systems.
The first project I was assigned to, was a project for the Antwerp fire department. Along with two other graduates and four seniors, I was thrown in at the deep end. I always had solid grades in school, and was fairly confident that I grasped the material I was taught.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My js data structures and algorithms now on GitHub</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/07/my-js-data-structures-and-algorithms-now-on-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2011 15:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/07/my-js-data-structures-and-algorithms-now-on-github/</guid>
      <description>If you have been reading my blog lately, you know that I&amp;rsquo;m implementing some data structures and algorithms in JavaScript. So far, I have blogged about simple sorting algorithms, the stack data structure and the queue data structure. This week I have also implemented a doubly linked list. I started writing a post about that last implementation, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t like where it was going, so instead of writing about it, I have pushed everything to a public Git repository.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Have you ever typed code on a job interview? Results</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/06/have-you-ever-typed-code-on-a-job-interview-results/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2011 14:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/06/have-you-ever-typed-code-on-a-job-interview-results/</guid>
      <description>As more established bloggers have argued before, there is something essentially wrong with job interviews in our industry. Software companies hire developers without even making them touch a keyboard. As long as you talk the walk you are able to land yourself a decent position. There are complete lists of .NET interview questions out there, which should, with enough preparation, make it possible for a somewhat technologiable person to ace the average .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reviewing and renewing resolutions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2010/12/reviewing-and-renewing-resolutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2010 20:17:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2010/12/reviewing-and-renewing-resolutions/</guid>
      <description>My career
I&amp;rsquo;m still working on the same projects as I was last year: Firestation Antwerp and Ghent. This year we did not build a lot of brand new things, but we have added a decent amount of new functionalities. Next to that there were a bunch of bugs to fix and technical debt to pay off. I learned a lot from the mistakes we made and refactoring makes you really think about what good and clean code should look like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 popular posts of 2010</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2010/12/top-5-popular-posts-of-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2010 17:25:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2010/12/top-5-popular-posts-of-2010/</guid>
      <description>Today I have spent a few hours evaluating this year&amp;rsquo;s analytics of my blog. In total I posted 59 entries this year, but in this post you will only find the 5 most popular, plus the ones that I liked writing a lot but failed to make it to the top 5.
The most popular posts of 2010
  Cannot start Service from the command line or debugger.: The most popular post of 2010, almost all traffic was completely driven by search engines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking back, moving forward (New years post)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2009/12/looking-back-moving-forward-new-years-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2009 18:57:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2009/12/looking-back-moving-forward-new-years-post/</guid>
      <description>In this post I&amp;rsquo;m going to reflect on the year that&amp;rsquo;s almost finished and the year to come.
I came up with a few topics that are worth discussing in this post.
My career
I don&amp;rsquo;t think I ever mentioned where I work. The first of January I will be working 18 months for Ferranti. The only company I&amp;rsquo;ve worked for since I graduated.
The first project I&amp;rsquo;ve ever worked on was a rather big one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My trip to Madrid in ten pictures</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2009/11/my-trip-to-madrid-in-ten-pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2009 20:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2009/11/my-trip-to-madrid-in-ten-pictures/</guid>
      <description>Last week I went to Madrid with my family-in-law to visit my girlfriend&amp;rsquo;s brother and cousin.
Although our stay there was rather short (only four days), we visited some of the most impressive places in Madrid:
 - Stadium Real Madrid
 The Royal Palace Prado Museum Queen Sofia Museum Buen Retiro Park Plaza Mayor &amp;hellip;   As always my girlfriend took lots of pictures, you can find my favorites below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why code reviews should be a teamthing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2009/08/why-code-reviews-should-be-a-teamthing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2009 19:22:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2009/08/why-code-reviews-should-be-a-teamthing/</guid>
      <description>Often code reviews are done by one person, the technical lead of your team.
In my opinion it&amp;rsquo;s better to make each developer of your team do code reviews.
My arguments Having all developers doing code reviews enforces well-documented coding standards.. Which also leads to discussions about what these codings tandards should be. Each developer is forced to understand the workflow of an application which isn&amp;rsquo;t his, which expands his domain knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My holiday in France in five pictures</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2009/08/my-holiday-in-france-in-five-pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2009 19:12:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2009/08/my-holiday-in-france-in-five-pictures/</guid>
      <description>Last week I went on a holiday to France with my girlfriend and her family.
Because pictures say more than words..
One: The location - Laguepie, Albi
Two: The house and &amp;ldquo;la piscine&amp;quot;
Three: Me enjoying the sun
Four: Only in France you find a 1955 Peugeot 403 with numberplates just standing there next to the road
Five: Random picture of one of the towns next to Laguepie
Looking forward to the next holiday :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Being a developer in India</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2009/02/being-a-developer-in-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2009 20:45:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2009/02/being-a-developer-in-india/</guid>
      <description>Nowadays all you here is: hey let&amp;rsquo;s outsource our call center, our IT department, our developer team.. to India. I asked Mudassar Ahmed Khan a few questions about how it&amp;rsquo;s like being a developer in India.

How is it like to be a developer in India?Quite bad..
 You get into heavy competition from day one when you join a Computer Science course. Companies set percentage criteria for young graduates.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>