<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Refactoring on Jef Claes</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/refactoring/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Refactoring on Jef Claes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2013 17:35:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/refactoring/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Putting my IronMQ experiment under stress</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2013/03/putting-my-ironmq-experiment-under-stress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2013 16:10:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2013/03/putting-my-ironmq-experiment-under-stress/</guid>
      <description>Two weeks ago, I shared my first impressions of IronMQ. Last week, I looked at some infrastructure to facilitate pulling from IronMQ. This implementation worked, but I hadn&amp;rsquo;t put it under stress yet; &amp;ldquo;First make it work, then make it fast&amp;rdquo;, and all of that.
I arranged a simple scenario for testing: one message type - thus one queue, where there are eight queue consumers that simultaneously pull messages from that queue, and dispatch them to a handler which sleeps for one second.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organizing commands and queries</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2013/01/organizing-commands-and-queries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2013 18:23:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2013/01/organizing-commands-and-queries/</guid>
      <description>In the last few posts I settled on an architecture for handling commands and queries. A byproduct of the described approach, is that your codebase quickly racks up plentiful little classes; a class to hold data, and a handler to act on that data, for each use case.
There are a few ways you can go at organizing things.
Everything in one location
**
**When there is very little going on in your application, you can just dump everything in one location without getting hurt too much.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Separating command data from logic and sending it on a bus</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2013/01/separating-command-data-from-logic-and-sending-it-on-a-bus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2013 22:03:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2013/01/separating-command-data-from-logic-and-sending-it-on-a-bus/</guid>
      <description>In my first post on this topic, I started out with an attempt to limit abstractions to solely commands and queries. Commands and queries were self-contained and could be invoked by passing them to a context-providing generic handler. The drawback of this approach was that it made constructor dependency injection impossible. In a next post, I separated data from logic, but never got around to writing a dispatcher that associates command data with their handlers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commands with dependencies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2012/10/commands-with-dependencies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2012 16:57:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2012/10/commands-with-dependencies/</guid>
      <description>Also read: Separating command data from logic and sending it on a bus
Yesterday I wrote about an architecture which limits abstractions by solely introducing commands and queries. I shared a dead simple variation of this pattern, the advantages I experienced, and how I could still unit test the controller if I wanted to.
At the end of that post I wondered how I would be able to test commands in isolation; suppose the implementation doesn&amp;rsquo;t use a database this time, but a hairy, too low-level, third party webservice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commands, queries and testing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2012/10/commands-queries-and-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2012 17:45:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2012/10/commands-queries-and-testing/</guid>
      <description>Also read:
 Self-contained commands with dependencies Separating command data from logic and sending it on a bus  We need abstraction, but the amount of abstraction we really need depends, and should be assessed on a case-by-case basis. It seems advisable to grow abstractions, and to introduce them gradually.
That being said, in this post I want to talk about an architecture that tries to limit abstractions to solely commands and queries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Value object obsession</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2012/09/value-object-obsession/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2012 17:20:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2012/09/value-object-obsession/</guid>
      <description>Primitive obsession is one of the more popular (hyped?) code smells these days.
 Primitive obsession is the name of a code smell that occurs when we use primitive data types to represent domain ideas. For example, we use a string to describe a message or an integer to represent an amount of money.
 The antidote is creating a value object instead of using a primitive. A value object is an immutable object which (in its DDD definition) carries no identity, but is compared based on the value of its attributes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Servicelocator pattern stinks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2012/04/some-servicelocator-pattern-stinks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2012 20:33:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2012/04/some-servicelocator-pattern-stinks/</guid>
      <description>I have been working on a somewhat legacy codebase which makes use of the Servicelocator pattern. Although I always thought of Dependecy Injection to be the superior pattern, I was pleased to find some Inversion of Control implementation in there. Working with the codebase, I discovered first hand how easily, when used without caution and discipline, the Servicelocator pattern can introduce code rot.
I will walk you through some of the issues I have with the Servicelocator pattern, mostly looking at it from a test perspective.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Follow up: Eliminating redundant eventhandlers using a dictionary to map controls</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2010/07/follow-up-eliminating-redundant-eventhandlers-using-a-dictionary-to-map-controls/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2010 20:55:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2010/07/follow-up-eliminating-redundant-eventhandlers-using-a-dictionary-to-map-controls/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I blogged on &amp;lsquo;WebForms refactoring: Eliminating redundant eventhandlers using a dictionary to map controls&#39;. In this post I went from bad code to better code. A smart reader gave me some good pointers on how to improve this code some more. Another iteration was necessary.
Losing the LinqIn the previous iteration I used Linq to search my dictionary.
 1: var res = mappings.Where(map =&amp;gt; map.Key.Equals((CheckBox)sender)).First();  This is overhead, because the dictionary implements an indexer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebForms refactoring: Eliminating redundant eventhandlers using a dictionary to map controls</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2010/07/webforms-refactoring-eliminating-redundant-eventhandlers-using-a-dictionary-to-map-controls/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2010 21:35:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2010/07/webforms-refactoring-eliminating-redundant-eventhandlers-using-a-dictionary-to-map-controls/</guid>
      <description>Last week I came across a problem which seemed trivial at first sight, but turned out to be a pretty fun refactoring challenge.
The scenarioThe real problem was a bit more complex, but for simplicity&amp;rsquo;s sake I made this example. In this form there are three checkboxes which map with the textboxes next to them. If the checkbox gets unchecked the corresponding textboxes should be cleared.

First iterationI warn you.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>